第十九卷
Verse 19
八大地狱之最 称为无间地狱
The worst of the Eight Hells is called Continuous Hell
为无间断遭受大苦之意 故有此名
It has the meaning of Continuous Suffering. Thus the name
五年前
5 years ago
屯门大兴村
we started valet parking in Tuen Mun.
皇宫大酒楼门口的停车档
at Palace Restaurant in Tai Hing Estate
开张大吉
Tuen Mun.
我和弟兄们雄心壮志
We were full of ambition.
谁知道开张还不到半个月
But 2 weeks had hardly gone by
每天平均被人扫荡一点三次
and the cops started busting us every day.
一年内
Within one year
死了六个兄弟
6 of our brothers died.
佛祖保佑
Thanks to the Buddha, my life has been spared.
算命的说我是 "一将功成万骨枯"
"What thousands must die so that Caesar may become great."
不过我不同意
But I don't believe in destiny.
我认为出来混的
The rule of this game
是生是死要由自己决定
is to take fate in our own hands.
你们跟着我的日子最短
You are the newest in my gang.
底子最干净
Your records are the cleanest.
路怎么走 让你们自己挑啊
You can choose your own future.
好了
OK.
祝你们
I wish you guys
在警察部一帆风顺
every success in the police force.
干杯 各位长官
Bottoms up, officers.
十分钟前你进来过
you were here 10 minutes ago.
我桌上有几个档案夹?
How many files were on my desk?
六个 四个米色在左边
Six, sir. Four beige ones on the left
一个红色和一个白色在右边 长官
one red and one white on the right.
你觉得我这人人怎么样?
What do you think of me?
对不起长官 不清楚
Sorry, I'm not sure, sir.
不过长官今天早上应该很匆忙
But I know you're in a hurry today
因为您穿了不同的袜子
'coz your socks don't match.
27149 先出去
27149, you can go now.
是 长官
Yes, sir.
五百 快点给钱
You owe me $500.
行了 下个月发了薪水再给你
Okay, but wait till pay day next month.
我说了,他最适合做卧底
I told you he would make the best undercover cop
进了警校,就要遵守警校的规矩
Now that you're in the cadet school you should follow the rules
不守规矩的人,就好像他这样
Those who break the rules will be like him
滚蛋
They will be expelled
有没有人想跟他交换?
Who wants to trade place with him?
我想跟他换
I do
这是个长时间的卧底计划
this is a long-term undercover mission
你在警察学校的记录会被删除
Your records in the cadet school will be erased
只有我和重案组的黄督察
Only Superintendent Wong and I
知道你的身份
know of your identity
你接受的是一个非常危险的任务
This mission is highly dangerous
你清楚了吗?
is that clear?
是,长官
Yes, sir
黄Sir,我真的撑不下去啦
Sir, I can't stand it any longer
不是被警察骚扰
I'm either harassed by cops
就是被古惑仔打
or beaten up by gangsters
4927,你是新人
4927, you are still a rookie
凭什么令我满意推荐你升级?
Give me a good reason why I should promote you
撑,你来试试啊,怎么撑啊
Hang on? Why don't you go hang yourself instead?
我在警校拿了优异奖
I won the Silver Whistle Award at the cadet
在学期间获得了高度评价
and have received numerous kudos as an officer
长官,我有信心可以领导警队
I am confident I can lead the police force sir
琛哥
Boss
是，知道了
OK, I got it
走
Move forward
快点
Hurry up
现在你到那边去拍张照
Please go over there to take your mugshot
请问
Excuse me
- 有没有人? - 什么事
- Hello? - Can I help you?
啊 没有没有 我想试试那个
Can I try this stereo?
你用什么喇叭?
What speakers are you using?
没有 有什么好介绍的?
Nothing special, any recommendations?
这部 标准港产货 一万多
Try this tube amplifier, made in Hong Kong, 10 grand only.
加上千多块的本地线
And use this cable, also locally made about 1000.
比得上十几万的欧洲货
The sound is as good as expensive European amps.
高音甜 中音准 低音沉
Sweet high notes, crisp middle, strong bass.
总之一句话 就是通透
In a word, transparent.
来 过来听听
Come and listen.
立体感多强
Human voices are drifting towards you.
感觉到没有?
See that?
就好像在你面前唱一样
Voices are indeed drifting towards you.
你试试这个
Try this one.
你听老音乐呢 这种好
This is ideal for listening to oldies.
怎么样?
What do you think?
真的不错
Much better indeed.
要是我买一整套 有折扣没有?
Any discount if I buy the whole set?
胆机在这儿买
Buy the tube amp here
喇叭就不要了
but not the speakers.
祥威便宜点
Go to Cheung Wai; it's cheaper there.
我找谁啊?
Whom should I ask for?
你就说阿仁介绍的
Just tell them Yan sent you.
哪张是我的?
Which one is mine?
中间那张
The one in the middle.
OK 谢谢
Okay, thanks.
谢了
You're welcome.
现在去祥威有人在吗?
Is Cheung Wai open yet?
有啦
Sure.
喂 你臭小子
You bastard.
我叫你帮我看着 你吃里爬外
I told you to watch the store not to send my customers away.
你的喇叭是卖得贵嘛
But your speakers are over-priced.
我不卖贵点
If I don't sell them at this price
哪有钱交保护费给你们这些老大呀?
how can I afford to pay "protection money"?
那你不交试试看啦
You can try not paying for a change.
哎 我的线
Hey, the cable.
借用两天
I'll return it in a few days.
四千多块 你借用两天
$4,000 for a few days?
去哪儿呀?
Where are you rushing to?
去送殡
A funeral.
你说
Tell me.
你光是伤人已经好几次了
How many times have you been busted for assault?
我千方百计和律政司说
I am trying to convince the Department of Justice
你心理有问题
that you have psychological problems
叫你看心理医生
and need to see a shrink.
你还到处打人
But you keep on beating people up.
你是不是真的心理变态?
Are you really going nuts?
你忘了自己是好人还是坏人了?
Have you forgotten you're a cop?
明明说好三年 三年之后又三年
You told me it's only for 3 years.
三年之后又三年
But after 3 years come another 3 years, and another.
就快十年了 老大
It's almost 10 years already, boss.
你对我态度好点行不行?
Can't you be a bit more courteous to me?
现在全香港只有我知道你的身份
I'm the only one in Hong Kong who knows your real identity now.
我回去把你的档案全都删除掉
Maybe I'll just erase your file
你一辈子做古惑仔 我也不用烦了
so you can stick with the Triads for good.
你想我怎么样
What do you want me to do?
天天提醒自己 我是警察
Remind myself I'm a cop every day?
做梦的时候都说
Shouting out "Drop your gun, I'm a cop."
"放下枪 我是警察!"这样?
even in my dreams?
韩琛什么时候进货?
When will Sam place his order?
不知道
No idea.
这个星期
Sometime this week.
什么?
What?
这个星期之内
Sometime this week.
泰国佬已经来了
The Thais are here.
韩琛收了货 去卖给别人
Once the goods arrive, Sam will resell them.
货仓在哪儿?
Where is the warehouse?
我怎么知道那货仓在哪儿?
How the hell do I know?
我才跟了他三年
I started working for him only 3 years ago.
这案子一破就退休
Okay, I'll let you retire after this.
你少来
Bullshit.
这句话我听了九千多次
I heard this a zillion times already.
又是这些破玩意儿(偷听器)?
Shit. These mikes again?
警察部那么有钱
The Police is loaded with cash
能不能换点先进的
tell them to get more advanced models.
植入体内的 要不要?
How about implanting it into your body?
植在哪儿?
Into which part of my body?
针孔摄影机
A pinhole camera?
针孔在哪?
Where's the lens?
二十五号是你生日嘛 臭小子
Your birthday is on the 25th, right?
我从来不戴表
I never wear watches.
怎么样?
So?
如果五点前不把数据交给国际刑警
If we got nothing for the Interpol by 5pm
假护照这个案子就麻烦了
the counterfeit passport case is off.
三点一刻啦
3:15. Tea time.
头儿 喝什么?
What would you like, boss?
热奶茶
Tea with milk, please.
他们什么都不肯说全部都说要等律师来
They won't talk without their attorney.
那些律师到现在还没回复
Has paged their lawyers but he hasn't called back yet.
律师没来 我什么都不会说
I won't talk without my attorney.
我是刘律师
I am Mr. Lau, your attorney.
有没有打电话回家?
Did you call home?
打回去干吗?
Why should I call home?
没打就好
It's good then.
上个星期五 十七号
Where were you
下午三点四十五分到五点
last friday
你去哪里了?
from 3:45 to 5:00 pm?
毛哥叫我来问你
Brother Mo told me to ask you
家里有没有什么要帮忙的
if yourfamily needs any help.
不用到处看
No need to look around.
律师在这儿 警察不可以录像
They won't record anything when a lawyer is present.
录下来也没用
It's not admissible in court anyway.
毛哥叫你来的?
Brother Mo sent you?
隔壁你那两个手下
Those 2 kids next door
把货场工厂供出来了
have squealed on the workshop already.
现在警察正赶过去
Cops are heading there now.
毛哥叫我来通知你 别乱说话
Brother Mo told you not to say anything.
如果有亲弟弟在那儿
If your brother is there
通知他
tell him to leave right away.
叫他先走
Here.
怎么样?
What?
走啊
Scram.
叫你走啊 听见没有?
I ask you to scram, do you hear?
快点走啊
Scram right away.
好 那我先走
All right! I'll leave you.
既然你不信
If you don't trust me, so be it.
自己小心点
Take care.
对了 律师没来之前 千万别乱说话
Remember don't talk without your attorney
还用你教我
I don't need you to tell me that.
Fanny.
哎
Yes?
来
Take this.
打电话
Check this number.
行啦
Sure.
帮我把消息发出去
Send this message for me.
牛头角长辉工业大厦二楼
Ngau Tau Kok Cheung Fai Industrial Building, 2nd Floor.
查到了
Get it.
牛头角长辉工业大厦二楼 OK
Ngau Tau Kok, Cheung Fai Industrial Building, 2nd Floor. OK.
头
Boss.
行了
All set.
古惑仔
A Triad member.
我的奶茶呢?
Where's my tea?
在这
Here.
谢了
Thanks.
对了 有两下子
You're great.
你怎么知道工厂是阿毛的?
How did you know it's Mo's hideout?
谢谢
Thanks.
喂 啊...
Hello, yes.
没问题 好
No problem. OK.
弟兄们 不好意思 晚上要加班
Sorry guys, over time tonight.
这次的目标是一个贩毒集团
Our target tonight is a drug trafficking cartel.
情报说一个钟头之后
In an hour's time
他会跟一个泰国的卖家交易
they will be trading with a Thai seller.
交钱地点就在对面大厦
Cash will be handed over in the building across the street
三楼的一个单位里边
in a unit on the 3rd floor.
但是交货的地点还不知道
Where the goods will be delivered is still unknown.
情报科的同事会负责追踪目标
CIB shall tag the target
监听还有管理通讯
and tap the phone lines.
重案组的同事 就等我接到卧底通知
Our unit will not take action
具体的交货地点之后才可以抓人
till our mole has pinned down the delivery location.
我们来看今晚的主角
Let's take a look at our principal stars.
这几个就是今晚的主角
Here are our principal stars tonight:
韩琛 陈永仁 迪路
Hon Sam, Chan Wing-yan, Del Piero.
我们已经监视他们很久了
We've been watching them for a long time.
希望这次能抓到他们
We'd better nail them tonight.
OK 没问题
OK? No more questions?
行动
Let's get to work.
不好意思 这么晚才找你
Sorry for paging you so urgently.
你知道 这案子事前要保密的
But our mission is kept confidential till the last moment.
没关系
No problem.
有没有信心?
Do you have confidence?
没什么
Yes, it should be OK.
喂 老爸?
Hello, Dad.
你叫老爸听
Pass the phone to Dad.
我没时间回去吃饭了
I can't come home for dinner.
饭做了总得吃嘛
Too bad, dinner has been prepared already.
下班打电话给我 我给你热热
Call me when you're back. I'll heat it up for you.
这么轻松?
You look so relaxed.
工作嘛 这次不行下次啰
It's only work. We can always work on it next time.
对不起
Sorry.
这区的手提电话和无线电波
All cell phone signals in this area
全部进入监听状态
are under surveillance.
黄警官
SP Wong.
黄警官 哪个频道?
SP Wong, which channel?
Channel 454870.
注意 麻雀到了
Attention. Our prey is in sight.
大哥
Big Brother.
琛哥
Boss.
电话都拿出来
Take out all your cell phones.
你们俩准备车
You two, go get the car.
等等
Wait.
阿仁
Yan
接泰国佬来
escort the Thais here.
你们俩跟我来
You two, follow me.
小刘
Lau.
有
Yes.
韩琛和他手下的手提电话有没有打过?
Did Sam and his gang make any calls?
没有 应该换了电话
No. They probably changed their phones.
不如随机搜索这一区打出的电话
Let's search randomly for calls made from this area.
正在搜索
Searching.
这一区现在有
Some 6,500 cell phones
六千五百多个手提电话接通了
are being connected in this area right now.
光是山东街十二个收发器
267 cell phones are making calls
就有二百六十七个电话在用
through the 12 receivers on this street alone.
十分钟 一定能追到
Give me 10 minutes.
做得好
Good.
谢谢
Thank you.
好像发现我们了
Did they spot us?
喂 那两个家伙是不是盯着我呢?
Are those two over there watching us?
哪两个家伙盯着你?
Which two?
那两个家伙啊
Those two.
哪有人盯着你啊?
No one is watching you.
那两个 就是抱在一起的那两个家伙
Those two making out over there.
人家在亲热 盯着你?
They are just making out. Why would they be watching you?
你明星呀?
You think you're a movie star?
麻雀来了
Our prey is back.
阿叶 注意
Yip, watch our prey closely.
琛哥 泰国佬来了
Boss. The Thai guys are here.
你好
Hey man.
What's up?
你好
How are you?
雪茄
Cigar?
好不好?
Is that any good?
正点
Excellent.
香港冷不冷?
Is it cold in Hong Kong?
好冷啊
Very cold.
哇,中国话都会说,喔唷
You even know how to speak Cantonese.
那我就用中国话损你啦
How fantastic.
厉害 厉害 真厉害
Marvelous indeed.
你过奖啦
Thank you so much.
AA+
成交
Deal.
楼下HN397开出
Automobile license plate number HN397 is taking off.
重复 HN397开出
Repeat, Helen, Nelson, HN397 is taking off.
注意 楼下HN397要走了
Attention. HN397 is taking off.
重复 HN397
Repeat, Helen, Nelson, 397.
要不要派车跟踪他们?
Should we send a car to tail them?
大象 葵涌码头
Elephant, Kwai Chung Container Terminus.
收到 葵涌码头
Roger.
迪路 有人跟踪你们
Piero. You're being tailed.
带他们逛花园
Lead them in circles.
他们收到我们的频道
They know which channel we are on.
转到456855
Switch to channel 456855.
琛哥 那两个人到哪去?
Boss, where are those two going?
别担心 冷静点
Don'tworry, take it easy.
帮我招呼他们
Take care of the Thais for me.
对不起
Sorry, sir.
喂?
Hello?
为什么不用步话机呀?不知道转了频道?
Why don't you use the walkie talkie? You don't know we've switched channels?
你说完没有?
Are you done yet?
还说
Beat it.
迪路 有没有人跟着你?
Piero, are you being tailed?
继续逛
Keep driving around.
阿张
Cheung.
用刚才的频道再通知大象一次
Use the current channel to tell Elephant
说行动取消
that action has been cancelled.
是 长官
Yes, sir.
大象 今晚不打麻雀了
Elephant, no hunting tonight.
先回公司
Come back to the station.
收到
Roger.
搞定了
Done.
他们搞什么鬼?
What the hell is going on?
等这么久 快冻死人啦
Our guys are freezing to death out there.
什么这么好笑啊?
What's so funny?
我会听泰文呢 我知道他说什么
I speak Thai. I know what they're saying.
是不是?
Really?
是啊 在那里数落琛哥 还发脾气呀
Yes. They are bitching at the boss
干嘛发这么大的脾气?
What are they bitching about?
这些泰国人啊 在龙鼓滩就快冻死了
Those Thais at Lung Koo Bay are freezing to death.
你也知道 泰国人怕冷啊 对不对?
You know they can't stand the cold.
有两下子啊 别闹了
That's right.
聪明啊
You're sharp.
冷静一点 一下车马上拍他
Calm down, when you get off immediately catch him
我正在过去呢 小心有狗啊
I'm on my way, Be careful cop
阿张 通知大象
Cheung, call Elephant.
龙鼓滩收货
Goods to be delivered at Lung Koo Bay.
怎么样?琛哥 找到了
Boss, I've found it.
叫傻强点点货 够不够分量
Tell Keung to check the goods.
看清楚周围有没有警察
And make sure no one is around.
嘿 这连鬼影子都没有
Not a soul.
有艘快艇靠近沙滩 应该开始验货
A boat is approaching. Probably for checking the goods.
喂 可卡因数量没错
The cocaine is all here.
傻强 你疯啦!
Keung, are you an idiot or what?
琛哥
Boss.
我都听到了
I heard it.
你叫他大声说一次
Tell Keung to shout loudly
可卡因是他的
that the cocaine is his.
傻强 是琛哥
Keung, the Boss.
大声的再说一次 可卡因是你的
asks you to shout aloud that the cocaine is yours.
哦 可卡因是你的
The cocaine is yours.
收货
Take delivery.
他们收货 准备抓人
They are taking delivery. Get ready for action.
谢谢 谢谢
Thanks. Thanks.
谢谢
Thank you.
小八
Double Eight.
泰国佬一出门口就抓人
As soon as the Thais step out, arrest them.
有内鬼 终止交易
There's a stooge. Stop the deal.
等等
Wait.
有内鬼 终止交易
There's a stooge. Stop the deal.
喂?
Hello?
把货扔海里 快点
Cast all the goods into the sea. Now.
傻强 把货扔海里
Keung. Cast all the goods into the sea.
站住 我们是警察
Police. Freeze.
站住 我们是警察 别跑
Police. Freeze
抓到人了
We got the men but lost the goods.
货被他们扔下海了
They have cast everything into the sea.
小八 等等 等等
Double Eight, hold it.
全部跟我来
All of you, follow me.
看什么 看什么 看什么?
What are you looking at?
琛哥 我看
Boss. Let's...
警察 别动
Police, don't move.
琛哥
Sam.
胃口很好嘛 不错
Yourfood looks good.
不错
Not bad.
我们查清楚了
We've straightened it out.
你两个手下在沙滩那吹风
Your boys are only strolling on the beach.
那可以放他们走了?
So they can go now?
行 随时都行
Sure, any time.
不再麻烦琛哥你啦 你这么忙
We don't want to waste any more of your precious time.
大家这么熟 别那么多废话啦
We've known each otherfor so long. Don't give me that.
我也很久没在这儿吃东西啦
I haven't had my dinner here for quite a while.
你喜欢 随时来都行
If you like it, you're always welcome here.
明天吧
How about tomorrow?
算了吧
I'll take a rain check.
买水果钱都没有 怎么好意思?
I feel bad coming here empty-handed.
不用客气
Don't stand on ceremonies.
是我不好意思
I should feel bad
连累琛哥今天晚上损失了几千块
for making you drop several grand tonight.
在我身边安插一个孬种就可以赶绝我啊?
You think planting a mole in us will do us in?
大家都一样
Same here.
哦 我想起一个故事
I remember a story.
有两个傻瓜在医院里边等着换肾
Two fools are waiting for their kidney transplants
但肾呢 就只有一个
but only one kidney is available.
那么两个人就玩一个游戏
The two guys thus play a game.
一个人把一张牌摆在对方的口袋里
They each put a playing card into the other's pocket.
谁猜到对方拿什么牌放到自己的口袋里谁就算赢
Whoever guesses the card in their own pocket wins.
你知道我看你什么牌了
You know I can see your card.
我都相信是
I think so too.
我赢定了
I will beat you.
行了
Let's see.
好 大家小心点
We should be more careful.
好
I will.
哦 忘了告诉你了
By the way
如果谁输的话就会死
whoever loses the game will die.
看你什么时候死
Let's see when you're gonna die.
你见过有人去摈仪馆和死尸握手吗
Ever seen someone shakes a corpse's hand?
走
Let's go.
放沙发旁边好了
Put it next to the couch.
好
OK.
谢谢
Thanks.
Mary
装修师傅几号电话?
What's interior designer's number?
装修师傅 90255047
The interior designer... 90255047.
哎哟 我刚才数到第几箱啦?
How many boxes have I counted?
24?真的?
24? Are you sure?
Sure(真的)
Sure
把电话给我
Pass me the phone.
哦 来来来
Coming.
喂?
Hello?
哦 等等啊
Hold on please.
干什么?谁啊?
Who is it?
不知道
I don't know.
喂
Hello.
是我
It's me.
对 在搬家呢
Yes, I'm moving in.
别偷听 在说秘密
Don't eavesdrop. It's confidential.
我整批货没了
I lost all of my goods.
查一下
There's a mole.
谁是卧底
Dig him outfor me.
你等等 这人多
Hold on, too many people around here.
等等
Hold on.
卧底的档案我不能碰 我查不到
I have no access to those undercoverfiles. I can't dig him out.
我不管有多困难
I don't care how difficult it is.
我只知道他用的是摩斯密码
I only know he uses Morse codes.
那好 你把昨天晚上那些人的资料全都给我
Give me all the information on the people around you last night.
真名啦 身份证啦 银行号码
Their real names, ID card no., account no., etc.
今晚见 13楼
See you tonight, at the cinema
就这样
OK.
怎么了?
What's the matter?
29啊
我在说我的小说 我写的那本小说
I'm talking about my novel.
我想到写什么了 来来来 过来 过来
I know what I'm going to write about. Come here.
我可以写那个男主角有二十八种性格
I can write about a man with 28 different personalities.
你是说我啊?
Are you talking about me?
你正经一点嘛
Be more serious.
喂 你想一想啊
Think about it.
一个人有二十八种性格
A man with 28 personalities.
也就是说 他每天起床就自己跟自己演戏
That means he starts role playing the minute he wakes up.
演得他连自己的
He is no longer certain
真实性格都忘了
which personality is the real him.
是不是很恐怖啊?
Isn't it scary?
很恐怖嘛
Very much.
很棒的
Good?
很棒 一定很畅销
Yeah. Will be a bestsellerfor sure.
喂 等等等等
Wait...
干嘛?
What is it?
凳子为什么这么大啊?
Why is the ottoman so big?
哪张啊?
Which one?
哎呀 我尺寸量大了 量错了
I must have gotten the measurements wrong.
你别这样 你别这样哦
Take it easy.
你们这些女孩子啊...
You women...
行了 行了 让我来看啊
Let me see. Get up slowly.
你别发脾气
Don't be mad.
见面?
Meet up?
你想我死呀?
You want me dead?
现在警局里有鬼
There's a mole in the police station
你先把他揪出来
Dig him outfirst.
那谁是啊?
So who is he?
好 我不跟你说了
I can't talk anymore.
什么?
What?
刚才?
Just now?
看跌打医生啊
I was at a Chinese chiropractor.
现在看心理医生
I'm seeing the shrink now.
我心理变态呀!就这样
I'm going psycho. That's it.
哇 这张椅子真是...太棒了
This chair is really... incredible.
那你应该买一张回家
Why don't you get one for yourself?
不用每次都来这边睡
So you don't need to come here and sleep every time.
你这里舒服一点嘛
It's more comfortable here.
别这么小器
Don't be so peevish.
这四个月 要不是我每个星期来睡一觉
During these 4 months, if it weren't for me
你那有时间打游戏机
you wouldn't have the time to play computer games.
是五个月
It's 5 months.
还有一个月 你的强制性治疗就结束
In one more month, your mandatory therapy will be over.
到时你能回家慢慢睡了
You can sleep peacefully at home then.
这么快结束啊?
So soon?
但是我好像没什么进展
I don't seem to have improved at all.
要不你写个报告 让我多看一段时间
Why don't you just prolong my treatment.
哦对 还有 最近我的头呢...好像要裂开似的
Besides, my head is splitting these days.
会不会是精神分裂啊??
Could it be schizophrenia?
这叫头痛 我开点必理痛给你
This is called "headache". I'll prescribe some Panadol for you.
其实有件事我想问你
Actually, there's something I want to ask you
但又觉得
but...
好像有点不太好意思
it's kind of embarrassing.
你觉得我人怎么样?
What do you think of me?
就是说 你觉得我是一个好人呢 还是个坏人?
Do you think I'm a good guy or a bad guy?
我都不知道你是什么人
I hardly know who you are.
告诉你一个秘密 不要告诉别人
Tell you a secret, but don't tell anyone.
其实我是警察
I'm actually a cop.
我也是
So am I.
下个星期继续
Let's continue nextweek.
要记住你做过的梦
Try to remember your dreams.
记得
Of course.
梦见你咯
I will dream about you.
下星期见
See you nextweek.
真的只有必理痛?
Just Panadol?
再见
Bye.
你的升职报告没问题
Your promotion should be OK.
我会调你到内务部
You will be transferred to Internal Affairs
不过在重案组上班
but you will work at OCTB.
不明白
I don't understand.
韩琛的案子没破 我怀疑有内鬼
I suspect Sam has a mole in the department.
想你去查一下
I want you to investigate.
为什么要我去?
Why me?
我和老张 老陈选了很久了
We have scrutinized all possible candidates.
你是最合适的人选
You have an immaculate record
在情报科破了不少案子
and you have solved many cases in CIB.
做内部调查有机会接触管理层啊
Working in IA, you will get in touch with senior officials.
这是机会
That's a good opportunity.
对了 下星期我安排你上《警讯》
I've arranged for you to appear on TV.
打扮得帅一点
Remember to spruce up a bit. bit.
那我什么时候面试?
When will I meet the Board?
刚才已经面试啦
You just did.
来 你来试试 来 玩玩嘛
Come, take a stab.
谢谢
Thanks.
对了
By the way
你的婚礼筹备的怎么样?
how's the wedding?
差不多了
Everything's on schedule.
这就好
That's good.
快点结婚 人也会定性一点
You'll be more stable after marriage.
给大家一个好印象嘛
Your image will improve too.
你还有机会升的
You have chance offurther promotion.
对了 什么都要看长远一点
Yes, broaden your horizon.
要写真名字的
Fill in your real name.
这是我的真名啊
This is my real name.
你不知我叫迪比亚路啊?
You don't know Del Piero is my real name?
真的啊?
Is that so?
真的
Yes.
喂 填什么哪?
What are you guys writing?
哦 琛哥说 要交点资料上去
The Boss told us to fill in these forms.
一定是帮我们买强积金的
Must be setting up mandatory providentfunds for us.
MPF
You know, MPF.
哇 你这么大个人
Are you serious?
保镖的镖都写错?
You don't even know to spell "bodyguard"?
不是这个啊?
Isn't it supposed to look like this?
当然不是这个啦
Of course not.
木字边的嘛
Should be B-O-D-Y-G-A-R-D.
是这个呀
That's it.
下个礼拜进货
A shipmentwill come in nextweek.
风声紧
They are watching closely.
你做你的事
You do what you need to do.
我这边你不用担心管
I'll handle the rest.
正在查内鬼 我怕我帮不了你
The file is open. I'm afraid I can't handle it.
原来你不是担心我
So you're notworried about me.
你是担心你自己啊 刘警官
You are worried about yourself, Inspector Lau.
哇 这女的长这么丑啊
Those girls are so ugly.
尽快帮你办妥
I'll take care of it as soon as I can.
喂?
Hello?
现在回来
I'm on my way back.
阿仁
Yan.
跟我多久了?
How long have you worked for me?
三 四年了吧
3 or 4 years already.
有这么久吗?
That long?
不觉得呀
Doesn't seem that long to me.
下个礼拜我想再进一批货
I have another shipment nextweek.
不过这次
But this time
我想找一些生面孔 又靠的住的兄弟
I'm using some tough, new faces.
你们休息一下
So you guys can rest.
傻强他们也不用啊?
Even Keung and the others?
傻强?
Keung?
傻强是傻瓜嘛
Don't you know he's nuts?
你知道吧 公司里有内鬼
There's a mole within us. You know that?
你觉得应该怎样做?
What do you think we should do?
我解决它
I'll take care of it.
怎么解决?
How?
这两天我会把他揪出来 你准备一下
I'll find outwho he is in a couple of days. Get ready for action.
阿仁
Yan.
这么多兄弟 我最信你了
Of all the brothers, I trust you the most.
小刘 小刘 早啊 来来来来
Lau.
来一根 不要了
No, thanks
兄弟们
These folks.
差不多你都认识 用不着介绍了
You know most of them no need for introduction, right?
不是 我是说...
No, but...
怎么?
Why?
他们怎么?
They are so...
在这时候来啊 谁都知道你查内鬼
Who doesn't know you're sent here to find the mole?
怎么样?来杯咖啡吧?
What do you want them to do? Pour you a cup of coffee?
不遭人嫉是庸才 对不对?
Only an idiot will not be envied, right?
不不过他们谁都想查出来那个内鬼到底是谁
They all want to know who the mole is
如果你想查谁尽管说
Just tell me whom you want to investigate.
好
OK.
有线索吗?
Any clues?
两天以前呢 我的卧底
Two days ago, my informer
差一点查到这个内鬼是谁
nearly found outwho he was.
不过可惜被他跑了
Too bad he lost him.
但我想韩琛要出货呢
But if Sam is getting a new shipment
他一定会再找这个内鬼的
he must contact the mole again.
我想盯着韩琛 应该行
Justfollow Sam and we'll getwhatwe want.
有道理 多教我两招
That's right. I've much to learn from you.
你千万别这么说
Don't say that.
上头一定觉得你有本事才派你来的
Our seniors sent you here because they think you can do it.
你以为内务部的工作谁做都行啊?
Not everyone can handle IA tasks.
这里太闷了
It's stuffy here.
出去聊吧
Let's get out of here.
重案组的咖啡啊 是总部最好的
The coffee here is the best in the headquarters.
你也来一杯
I'll pour you a cup.
我的卧底差一点查到这个内鬼是谁
My informer nearly found outwho the mole was.
但我想韩琛要出货呢
But if Sam is getting a new shipment
他一定会再找那个内鬼
he must contact the mole again.
喂?
Yes?
喂
Hey.
怎么?
Yes?
床到了
The bed has arrived.
到啦?舒不舒服?
Is that so? Comfortable?
你要不要试一试啊?
You want to try it?
神经 赶稿子呢
Don't be silly. I have work to do.
考虑一下
Think about it.
不考虑 不考虑
No, I can't.
来嘛
Come on.
下个星期六
Saturday.
下个星期六有空再跟你试
I'll be free next Saturday. We can try it then.
好吧
OK.
星期六
OK, next Saturday then.
再见
Bye.
Bye
醒了?
Up already?
醒了
Yes.
你刚刚试完床 又工作啦?
We just tested the bed and you are working again?
勤奋嘛
I'm very hardworking.
写到哪儿啦?
What are you writing now?
写到这里了
Here.
其实这本书的男主角挺惨的
The more I think of it, the more pathetic the main character appears.
恩 很惨
Pathetic indeed.
真的?那写好一点
Perhaps I should make him a happier guy.
好 好
Good.
写他做回好人吧
Should I turn him into a good guy?
他是个好人 不过他又做错事
Even though he is good he has done bad things.
那结局应该怎么样啊?
So how should it end?
结局呢也是个问题
That's a good question.
不过就留给你们这些文人吧
I'll leave this to you writers.
你不睡?帮帮忙嘛
You're not going to sleep? Help me, please.
你不睡?
Help me, please?
我不行
I can't.
你先睡吧 你太累了
Go to sleep. You are tired.
大B 从今天开始
From now on
二十四小时跟着黄警官
follow SP Wong around the clock.
迪路啊 我知道怎么样分辨谁是警察了
Piero, I know how to spot a plainclothes.
怎么分?
How?
总之那个人在做事情
If he seems to be doing something
但又不专心的做事情看着我们的
but is paying attention to us instead
那就应该是警察
then he is a cop.
对呀
Is that so?
满街都是警察?
Then the whole place is filled with cops.
好多的啊
They're everywhere.
阿仁
Yan.
琛哥
Boss.
看什么?
Watching something?
你是警察
You are a cop.
我们在猜谁是警察
We are guessing who a cop is.
靠 这么无聊
How trivial.
按摩去不去?
I'm going for a massage, wanna come?
我最讨厌了
I hate it.
别跟人说哦
Don't tell.
我就说
Tell on him.
我不说
I won't.
这么巧?
What a coincidence.
对呀 刚好在这附近买东西
Yes, I was shopping in the hood.
很久没见了
Haven't seen you for ages.
六 七年了吧
6 or 7 years already
还好吗?
How are you?
我结婚了 你呢?
I'm married. How about you?
还在道上混?
Still working in...?
妈咪
Mommy.
你女儿啊?
Your daughter?
嗯
Yes.
多大了?
How old is she?
五岁
5 years old.
我在等我老公来接我 所以...
I'm waiting for my husband's car, so...
我也赶时间
I'm also in a hurry.
Bye
Bye.
妈咪 我今年六岁啦
Mommy, I'm 6 already.
对不起 妈咪说错了
Sorry, I always get itwrong.
你在哪啊?
Where are you now?
正过来啦
On my way.
喂
Hello?
头 搭站坐地铁过海
Boss, he is taking the subway.
跟着他
Keep following him.
喂 头 他上了24楼
Boss, he has gone to the 24th floor.
继续监视他
Stay put. Don't do anything rash.
琛哥 查到了
Boss, we've got him.
不知道
I don't know yet.
不过我知道他现在在哪
But I know where he is now.
在这里盯着
Keep watch over here.
怎么样?有什么好消息?
So? Any good news?
下个星期有批货到
A shipmentwill come in nextweek.
时间地点还不知道
Time and location yet to be confirmed.
韩琛的卧底到现在还没有查到
I still don't know who Sam's mole is
不过他好像很有把握把我挖出来
but he seems confident he can blow my cover.
把你挖出来?
In that case
这样的话不要玩啦 我们输定了
we'd better stop it. We're gonna lose for sure.
不会吧?
You are kidding, right?
什么不会?会死人的
What else can we do? It's deadly business.
喂
Hello?
琛哥打电话来说 找到了那个内鬼
Boss said he had found the mole.
叫我们去解决他
He told us to take care of him.
我马上到
I'll be right there.
喂
Hello?
看着黄警官
Keep an eye on SP Wong.
大个子 阿牛 走楼梯
You two, take the stairs.
傻强 坐那部电梯
Keung. take the elevator.
有没有人知道你来见我?
Anyone knows you're seeing me today?
没有
No.
现在他们在楼下
They are downstairs now.
干什么?
What are you doing?
把它收起来
Put it away.
你从上面走吧
Take the window-washing scaffolding.
你呢?
How about you?
我坐电梯咯
I'll take the elevator.
小心
Be careful.
没什么
Nothing.
喂 老婆 观澜湖的楼好棒啊
Darling, the apartment is superb.
一百八十度玻璃 正对着高尔夫球场啊
A 180-degree window facing the golf course
还有会籍啊 一百万都不用啊
plus club membership costs less than a million.
黄警官
Superintendent Wong?
麻烦你 兜去正门
Turn around to the main entrance.
你觉得我这人怎么样?
What do you think of me?
二十五号是你的生日嘛 臭小子
Your birthday is on the 25th, right?
仁哥 快走啊
Let's go.
警察!走啊!
Police. Let's go.
头 麻烦了
Bad news, Boss.
黄Sir出事了
Something happened to SP Wong.
下午时分 在上环区发生的枪击案
There's a gunfight in Sheung Wan this afternoon.
三名凶徒死亡
Three suspects were dead
另外多名凶徒 警员和市民受伤
several suspects and pedestrians were injured.
警方证实 其中一名死者的身份
The police confirmed that one of the victims
是有组织及三合会调查科
was a superintendent in OCTB
警司黄志诚
Mr Wong Chi-shing.
行凶动机未明
The motive is unknown.
警方不排除有仇杀成份
Possibility of gang feud is not ruled out.
现正通缉多名活跃于
They are now after several triad members
油尖旺区的黑社会分子
active in the Southern Kowloon area.
警务处长发表声明
The Police Commissioner
对黄志诚警司的死表示沉重的哀悼
expressed deep condolence
并且表示会尽快破案
and pledged to solve the case as soon as possible.
嘿 你都不知道刚才多险哪
Itwas a close shave.
你一说去按摩啊 都不到十分钟
10 minutes after you went to your massage
琛哥就说要做事了
Boss told us to get ready.
哇 我真是怕
I was scared stiff.
你知道我 一向来真格的溜到最后的嘛
You know, I hide under the car in every fight.
上去还有枪嘛
And there were guns up there.
我真想跟大家说 哇 我有事先走啦
I wanted to just sneak out of there.
前两天 琛哥他叫我去他的房间里头
Two days ago, Boss told me to go to his room.
他问我:傻强啊 你跟我多久了?
He asked me how long I'd worked for him.
我哪记得
How the hell could I remember?
然后他就说:傻强
He then said: Keung
你跟我五年了
it's been 5 years already.
你在这几年里头呢 都很能干
You've performed well all these years.
如果我有个问题想问你
I have a question for you.
就是说如果有兄弟是卧底
If one of your brothers is a mole
你敢不敢杀了他?
will you dare to take him out?
他就这样面对面问我 我当然说敢啦
Of course I said yes to his face.
你当我真的是傻瓜啊?
You think I'm an idiot?
结果怎么样呢
What's the result?
当然是找不到那个卧底啦
Of course they couldn'tfind the mole.
哇 那个警察硬骨头
The cop was tough.
把他抓了上去
They dragged him upstairs
他们把他抓了上去 足足打了十分钟
and beat him up for a good 10 minutes.
十分钟
10 minutes...
一句话都没有说过
He didn't say a word.
傻强
Keung.
琛哥说
Boss said...
那个警察很会掩饰
the cop was hot on his trail.
今天谁没出现 谁就是卧底
Who didn't show up today is the mole.
我没有
I didn't...
我没说你去按摩
tell him you wentfor a massage.
让琛哥知道你去按摩 你肯定倒霉了
If Boss knew, you're dead meat.
仁哥 我好想问你
Yan, I want to ask you something.
今天那个按摩女郎漂亮吗?
How was the masseuse today?
你知道
Because...
按摩女郎不漂亮那就没劲了
if she's ugly, it's notworth it.
快走
Leave right away.
撞了车 很多警察会来
There will be lots of cops after a car crash.
总之呢 你要记住
Anyway, remember this:
如果哪个人
If you see someone
他做事不专心 又看着你的话
doing something without paying attention to it but at the same time watching you
他就是警察
then he is a cop.
根据闭路电视的录像
According to the closed-circuit TV
黄警司是四点十五分进入大厦
SP Wong entered that building at 4:15 pm.
凶徒二十分钟后到达
The suspects entered 20 minutes later.
在四点三十八分
At 4:38 pm
我们收到刘警官的通知
we received Inspector Lau's report.
在我们到达大厦前八分钟 有人堕楼
8 minutes before we arrived, someone fell off the building.
那个是黄警司
That was SP Wong.
死的和受伤的疑凶 全都是韩琛的手下
All the suspects killed or injured belong to Sam's gang.
有很多疑凶跑了
Many suspects escaped.
人数不清楚
The actual numbers are unknown.
知不知道黄警司去那儿干什么
Do you know why SP Wong went to that building?
是我
Itwas me.
我叫CIB跟踪他
I told CIB to follow him.
你们CIB为什么跟踪黄警司?
Why was CIB following him?
这是内务部的事
That's IA's business.
现在黄警司死了
Now that SP Wong is dead
就和我们重案组有关系
it is OCTB's business.
你这是什么态度啊?
What kind of attitude is that?
黄警司尽忠职守 你找人调查他?
SP Wong was dedicated to the police force and you investigated him?
内务部又是什么态度啊?
What kind of attitude is that?
我们高层的事用不着你管?
So we seniors have to ask for your approval, huh?
现在你的人做错了
Your people have made a mistake now.
不然黄警司不会死 知道吗?
Or SP Wong wouldn't have died.
现在我跟你谈公事
I am talking about business here.
我跟你谈私事
I am talking about personal matters.
谁也想不到会这样 OK?
Nobody wanted this, OK?
对不起
Sorry, sir.
是我的疏忽
It's my negligence.
我会给大家一个交代
I will give everybody an answer.
对不起
Sorry.
黄警司的计算机里面
SP Wong has a file
有他派去韩琛那里做卧底的档案
with information on our undercover in Sam's gang.
不过有密码锁着
It is locked by a password.
但是计算机部的同事又解不开
The technical staff can't decipher it.
刘警官
Inspector Lau.
嗯
Yes.
你跟CIB 尽快想办法
Work with CIB
把它打开
to unlock it.
把那个卧底找出来 OK?
Find our man and get him out of there.
还有
By the way
黄警司是个好警察
SP Wong was a good cop.
他的葬礼 你们要办得风光一点
We should give him a grand funeral.
知道吗?
Okay?
是 长官
Yes, sir.
喂?
Hello?
喂 琛哥啊 怎么闹的这么大?
Boss. Why made such a scene?
那警察整天跟着我
He was following me all the time.
不是他死就是我亡啊
One of us would have to die.
这现在全由我负责
I'm now in charge of everything here.
如果要出货 打个电话给我
If you're having any transactions just let me know.
搞定了
It's done.
今天杀那警察的时候 那批货已经收了
We got the goods when they killed the cop today.
哪 不多说了哦 免得你烦
Okay, I won't bother you now.
为什么找我?
What did you call me for?
你就是那张牌?
So you're the one?
你是谁?
Who are you?
重案组刘健明
Inspector Lau of OCTB.
黄警司死了 大家都很不开心
SP Wong is gone. We're all upset
我还有点事情没做完
I still have unfinished business.
我看黄警司不想知道你犯法
SP Wong wouldn'twant you to take law in your hands.
你到底想怎么样?
What do you want?
合作
Co-operation.
我想我们两个合作可以反转韩琛
We can nail Sam by joining force.
今天下午 在上环发生的枪击案
The police has discovered
其中一名在逃的疑犯
the body of a fugitive suspect. He was involved in
警方在一小时前发现他的尸体
the Sheung Wan shooting earlier today.
经警方证实
The police has confirmed
是派去执行职务的卧底警察徐伟强
the body to be an undercover cop Tsui Wai-keung
警方对事件深表惋惜
The police has expressed their condolence
并表示会尽力追查
and promised a thorough investigation.
老板 仁哥回来了
Boss, Yan is back.
今天下午 元朗发生连环三车相撞
Three vehicles collided in Yuen Long today.
其中一辆轿车的司机被困
The driver of the private car was trapped
由消防员救出
until firefighters came and rescued him.
琛哥
Boss.
怎么样?阿仁
What is it, Yan?
我干掉了傻强
I have taken care of Keung already.
有没有找人看过那货仓?
Did you ever send him to the warehouse?
如果他知道在哪就麻烦了
Itwill be disastrous if he knows where it is.
琛哥
Boss. It's me.
你用不着自己去吧
You don't have to go yourself.
我不想有人知道密码
I don'twant anyone to know the password.
明白
I understand.
我帮你把人调开
I'll send everyone away.
张警官
Inspector Cheung.
叫跟踪韩琛的人回来
Tell those boys to stop following Sam's gang.
我收到消息 韩琛正要去他的货仓
I got information that Sam is heading towards the warehouse.
不撤走跟踪他的人 他是不会去货仓的
He won't go if he's being tailed.
要是真想帮黄警司
Just call them back.
做点事的话就现在下班
Let's do something for SP Wong.
你们帮帮忙好不好?
Please help me, OK?
你说句话嘛
Say something.
这件事跟我无关
This is not my case.
陈警司叫我别碰这件事
Officer Chan told me not to get involved.
如果大家肯下班 那下班咯
If they're willing to get off duty then it's up to them.
我知道黄警司的事情我要负上责任
I know I'm responsible for SP Wong's death.
但我跟大家一样
I am also a cop, like you.
我也是警察 我也是为了破案
I want to solve the case too.
你不是只想升职的吗?
I thought you only want promotion.
哪 是黄警司的卧底给的情报
It's SP Wong's mole who tipped me off.
你们信不信?
Do you believe it or not?
过了今晚可能就没机会了 你们想清楚啊
This is our last chance Are you ready to take the risk?
各单位注意 目标车辆
Attention: Target vehicle
现在由广东道转至三号干线
is on Highway no.3 from Canton Road.
三号码头调头
It's turning around at Pier 3
上龙翔道往观塘方向
on Lung Cheung Road towards Kwun Tong.
张警官 他们来了二十分钟
They have been here for 20 minutes
上了大厦停车场四楼
they are going to the 4th floor of the car park.
干什么?这案子陈警司不让我碰
Officer Chan won't let me touch this case.
出了娄子 你可自己负责
If anything goes wrong, you'll take the blame.
他们正在4P点货
They are loading the goods at 4P.
大象 在3P的出口准备
Elephant, stand by at the exit at 3P.
小八 守住2P的入口位置
Double Eight, watch the entrance at 2P.
还有 鱼丸和张警官会在这里准备
Fishball and Cheung, stand by here.
所有人等我的命令
All of you, waitfor my signal.
唉 忘了琛哥叫我垫后了
Oh, I forgot Boss told me to stay behind.
在前面放下我
Drop me off here.
撞他!
Run him over.
我算过命
My Master always said that about my life:
算命的说我是:一将功成万骨枯
"What thousands must die so that Caesar may become great."
路怎样走 你们自己挑了
You choose your own future.
你挑的
That's what you have chosen.
这杯咖啡是给你的
Coffee for you.
他等了你很久了
He's waited a long time for you.
是你呀?
So it's you?
那台机器怎么样?
Was the stereo OK?
很好
Pretty good.
胆机要预热
Those tube amps have to be warmed up.
预热十数分钟 声音更漂亮
Wait 10 minutes and it sounds great.
要不要给你送礼啊?
Should I salute you?
不用
Not, don't.
喂 做卧底多久了?
How long have you been an undercover?
我跟了韩琛三年多
I've followed Sam for 3 years.
以前跟过几个老大
I had several other bosses before.
加起来差不多有十年吧
All together it's been 10 years.
十年?
10 years?
那应该我送礼给你才行啊
I should salute you instead.
恢复我身份就行了
I just want an identity.
我只想做个普通人
An identity as a normal man.
厌了?
Getting tired?
你没做过卧底 你不懂
You've never been a mole, you won't understand.
可惜找不到那个内鬼
Too bad I still can'tfind the stooge.
找到了我一定不放过他
I'll take him down if I find him.
别想那么多了 给你恢复身份
Don'tworry. Let me give you back your identity.
我帮你打开那个档案 可是
I'll open your file but...
我没有密码
I don't have the password.
卧底摩斯密码是什么?
What's the Morse code for "undercover"?
就这么简单?
That's it?
哇 你这么大个人
Are you serious?
保镖的镖字都写错?
You don't even know to spell "bodyguard"?
不是这个?
Isn't it supposed to look like this?
当然不是这个啦
Of course not.
李医生
Dr. Lee.
还以为你不会来呢
I thought you wouldn't come.
警方在通缉你
You're wanted by the police.
能不能借你椅子睡一下?
Can I sleep in your chair again?
上去慢慢说吧
Let's talk upstairs.
你上次说你是警察
Last time you said you're a cop
是真的?
Is it true?
本来是
It was true.
不知道现在还是不是
But I'm not so sure now.
那你有什么打算?
So what's your plan?
不知道 正在想
I don't know. Still thinking.
有件事我早就想跟你说了
There's one thing I've been trying to tell you for a while.
不过一直觉得不好意思
But it's too embarrassing.
我整天做梦见到你这件事
I told you I dreamt about you all the time.
是真的
It's true.
我也是
Me too.
记着我们的秘密 再见
Remember my secret. Goodbye.
Mary
怎么了 坏了?
What is it? Has it broken down?
今天早上音响铺的人来过
This morning the guys from the stereo shop came.
他们帮你调过机器
They have tuned it up already.
还留了张CD给你试机
They also left a CD samplerfor you.
我听了
I've listened to it.
你吃早餐没有?
Have you had breakfast yet?
我去帮你买
I'll get you some.
冻奶茶?
Iced tea?
菠萝包?
Chinese buns?
好
Sure.
这本小说我写不下去了
I can'tfinish my novel.
我都不知道那个人是好人坏人
I don't know whether he's good or bad.
这个我看只有他自己清楚
I think only he knows.
下个礼拜进货
A shipmentwill come in nextweek.
风声紧
They are watching closely.
你做你的事
You do what you need to do.
我这边你不用担心
I will handle the rest.
正在查内鬼 我怕我帮不了你
The file is open. I can't handle it.
原来你不是担心我
So you're notworried about me.
是担心你自己啊 刘警官
You are worried about yourself, Inspector Lau.
声音漂亮吗?
Are the voices crisp enough?
这些珍贵的录音
The precious recording
是我在韩琛的办公室找到的
was taken from Sam's office.
你不走运
It's not your lucky day.
用不着唬我 想怎么样?
Don't threaten me. What do you want?
我想恢复身份
I want my identity back.
三点钟 港外线码头 开着电话
3 pm, Central Ferry Pier. Keep your cell on.
你现在拨的电话暂时未能接通
The number you have dialed cannot be connected.
请在讯号声后留下您的口讯
Please leave a message after the beep.
Mary 对不起
Mary, I'm sorry.
我选了做好人
I've chosen to be the good guy.
我现在就去见陈永仁
I'm going to meet Yan now.
不管怎么样 我会恢复他的身份
No matterwhat, I'll give him back his identity.
档案就在我的计算机里面
The file is in my computer
密码是你的生日
and the password is your birthday.
挺利索的
You sure know what you're doing.
我也读过警校
I also went to the cadet school.
你们卧底可真有意思 老在天台见面
Do all undercover cops like rooftops?
我不像你 我光明正大
Unlike you, I'm not afraid of light.
我要的东西呢?
So where's the stuff I want?
我要的你还未必带来呢
I don't think you've broughtwhat I want either.
什么意思?
So what does that mean?
你上来晒太阳的?
We came up here to sunbathe?
给我一个机会
Give me a chance.
怎么给你机会?
How?
我以前没得选择
I have no choice before
现在我想做一个好人
but now I want to turn over a new leaf.
好啊
Good.
跟法官说
Try telling that to the judge.
看他让不让你做好人
See what he has to say.
那就是要我死?
You want me dead?
对不起 我是警察
Sorry, I'm a cop.
谁知道?
Who knows that?
别动 警察
Don't move. Police.
放下枪 放了刘警官
Drop your weapon and let Inspector Lau go first.
你上司是韩琛的卧底
Your boss is Sam's mole.
证据在我手上
I got evidence.
我们到警察局再说
Let's clear this up at the station.
放下枪 立刻放下枪
Drop your weapon now.
我报了警啦
I've called the police.
我干嘛要相信你啊?
Why should I trust you?
你不用相信我
You don't have to.
你小心点
You'd better watch out.
Look who's talking.
祝你们在警察部一帆风顺
I wish you every success in the police force.
干杯 各位长官
Bottoms up, officers.
不用怕 大家同门师兄弟
No sweat. We are brothers.
现在琛哥死了
Sam is dead now.
以后你要罩着我
You have to look after me.
我九四年加入警校
I joined the cadet school in 1994.
可惜 这么多年都上不去
But my career never really takes off.
他连看都不看我一眼
Sam looked down on me.
韩琛的录音带我已经毁灭了
I've taken care of Sam's tape.
放心吧 以后我跟你了
Don'tworry. I'll follow you from now on.
警察快到了 做戏做全套
Ourfolks will be here any minute. Let's give them a good show.
其实我很能干 是琛哥不识货
I'm actually quite smart. Too bad Sam never knew that.
我是警察
I'm a cop.
六个月后 李心儿医生在去世的警校校长
Six months later, Dr. Lee Sum Yee was looking through the personal
叶Sir的遗物中 发现陈永仁的档案
properties left by Officer Yip Headmaster of the Cadet.
证实了他的警员的身份 陈永仁现
She found Chan Wing-yan's file that proved his police identity.
安葬在黄志诚警司的墓旁
Chan Wing-yan is now buried next to SP Wong Chi-shing.
你好吗?警察
How are you, Mr. Policeman?
不守规矩的人 就好像他这样
Those who break the rules will be like him
滚蛋
They will be expelled
你们有没有人想跟他交换?
Anybody wants to trade place with him?
我想跟他换
I do
佛曰:
Says the Buddha:
「受身无间者永远不死
"He who is in Continuous Hell never dies
寿长乃无间地狱中之大劫,」
Longevity is a big hardship in Continuous Hell"